<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on litblog</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on litblog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>&amp;copy; &lt;a href="https://github.com/carlo-colombo">Carlo Colombo&lt;/a> 2021</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 21:55:36 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing Elixir Buildpack</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/introducing-elixir-buildpack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 21:55:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/introducing-elixir-buildpack/</guid><description>Cloud Native Buildpack for Elixir</description></item><item><title>Deploy TiddlyWiki on Kubernetes</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/deploy-tiddlywiki-on-kubernetes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:02:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/deploy-tiddlywiki-on-kubernetes/</guid><description>Discovery of TiddlyWiki I discovered TiddlyWiki reading the blog of the late Joe Armstrong (of Erlang fame). After reading a post about Erlang and Elixir I started looking into other posts and I found his introduction to TiddlyWiki. The author presented how was using the wiki as his blog and as todo list systems.
I periodically start to investigate, use for a few weeks, and then abandon todo list systems. I went through at least Trello, Google Tasks, Google Keep, textfiles, command line tools, and probably some mobile app.</description></item><item><title>Decorate functions using macros in Elixir</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/track-functions-call-in-elixir-applications-with-google-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jun 2017 09:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/track-functions-call-in-elixir-applications-with-google-analytics/</guid><description>After I decided to make public a telegram bot to monitor bus time in Dublin (@dublin_bus_bot). Before the release I became curious to see how many people will use it (spoiler: just an handful) and I thought that would be a good idea to track the use on google analytics.
Overview Google analytics provide a measurement protocol that can be used to track things that are different from websites (mobile apps, IOT).</description></item><item><title>Serverless Telegram Bot on GC Functions</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/serverless-telegram-bot-on-gc-functions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 09:10:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/serverless-telegram-bot-on-gc-functions/</guid><description>I played for some time with the idea of having a telegram bot run serverless in the cloud. Obviously the code run on some server but it is not necessary to care to provision, deploy, starting the application, etc. All you care about is your code.
GC Functions can be triggered by Pub/Sub events, buckets events and HTTP invocations. The latter is the one that we are going to provide as webhook to Telegram to be invoked when a message is sent to our bot.</description></item><item><title>Using Docker Cloud on Scaleway vps</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/using-docker-cloud-on-scaleway-vps/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2016 11:54:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/using-docker-cloud-on-scaleway-vps/</guid><description>Docker cloud Docker Cloud (formerly Tutum) help to deploy containers image on node clusters. Nodes can be provisioned directly from the service (Digital Ocean, Azure, AWS, Packet.net, and IBM SoftLayer). Additionally is possible to use the function Bring your own node (BYON) to add any linux server connected to the internet as node and deploy on it.
I&amp;rsquo;m using this service to manage a stack (a set of images described by a file similar to docker-compose.</description></item><item><title>The 3 E: Elixir, Exrm, and Environment variables</title><link>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/the-3-e-elixir-exrm-and-environment-variables/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 21:05:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://carlo-colombo.github.io/post/the-3-e-elixir-exrm-and-environment-variables/</guid><description>Intro I’m building a bot for Telegram, once make a build with exrm I found myself some problem configuring the telegram api key using environment variables. I decided to share what I found because my google foo was not helpful at all.
TL;DR To configure en elixir application built with exrm use conform and load the environment variable in the trasforms section of the conform schema.
config.exs config.exs is where the configuration of elixir project are added.</description></item></channel></rss>